Finding Aid for Center for Research on Learning and Teaching (University of Michigan) publications
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The Center for Research on Learning and Teaching (University of Michigan) publications
1963-2008
1963-2006
University of Michigan. The Center for Research on Learning and Teaching.
04134 Bimu C537 2
Publications and other printed material produced by the University of Michigan Center for Research on Learning and Teaching including reports, newsletters, brochures, manuals and study guides.
1.25 linear feet
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Publications are received periodically from the unit. Donor No. 7926
The publications are open to research.
For historical note, please consult finding aid for The Center for Research on Learning and Teaching (University of Michigan) records.
The CRLT Publications (1.25 linear feet) include brochures, bulletins, manuals, newsletters, and reports of the CRLT. The CRLT bulletin Memo to the Faculty, which describes effective methods of learning, teaching and testing, sought to help faculty and teaching assistants improve their skills. The bulletin was first distributed in 1963, and ceased publication in 1982 due to budget cuts. A complete run is included in this subgroup. In 1987, CRLT began publishing a new bulletin entitled CRLT Occasional Papers, which once more focused on methods which could improve teaching and learning. A complete run is available, through 2007. Also included in bulletins is the Criteria for the Evaluation, Support, and Recognition of College Teachers, from 1976-1978. It published reports from research by the CRLT, supported by the Fund for the Improvement of Postsecondary Education, Department of Health, Education, and Welfare.
The publications also contains manuals, which include guidebooks for graduate student instructors on how to teach, resources and support services for new faculty members, and guides on using computers for instruction. Also included in the manuals is "Teaching Tips" by Wilbert McKeachie, who later became director of the CRLT.
The remaining publications are reports, providing the results of studies by the CRLT. The majority address the training of graduate student instructors, and the evaluation and improving of college instruction. There is also a report on the undergraduates at the University of Michigan from 1993.
Subjects:
University of Michigan. Center for Research on Learning and Teaching.; College teaching--Research.
Contributors:
Designing More Effective College Instruction Project.; Faculty Development Fund Teaching Award Program.; Fund for the Improvement of Postsecondary Education.
Genre Terms:
Bulletins.; Manuals.; Reports.; Brochures.; Newsletters.; Study guides.
- Publications
  - Abstract
    - Cumulative Index for Development and Experiment in College Teaching, 1974 (Box 1)
  - Brochures, 1995-2000; 2001-2008; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Bulletins
    - CRLT Occasional Papers
      - No. 1-23, 1987-2004; 3 folders (Box 1)
    - Criteria for the Evaluation, Support, and Recognition of College Teachers
      - No. 2-7, 1976-1978 (Box 1)
    - Memo to the Faculty
      - No. 1-12, 1963-1965 (Box 1)
        (includes Table of Contents for no. 1-59)
      - No. 13-18, 1965-1966 (Box 1)
      - No. 19-24, 1966-1967 (Box 1)
      - No. 25-30, 1967-1968 (Box 1)
      - No. 31-36, 1968-1969 (Box 1)
      - No. 37-42, 1969-1970 (Box 1)
      - No. 43-46, 1970-1971 (Box 1)
      - No. 47-50, 1972 (Box 1)
      - No. 51-54, 1973-1974 (Box 1)
      - No. 55-57, 1975-1976 (Box 1)
      - No. 58-61, 1976-1978 (Box 1)
      - No. 62-65, 1979-1980 (Box 1)
      - No. 66-71, 1980-1982 (Box 1)
  - Manuals
    - A Guidebook for Teaching Labs for University of Michigan Teaching Assistants, 1996 (Box 1)
    - A Guidebook for University of Michigan Teaching Assistants/Assistants/Graduate Student Instructors, 1988-2003; 4 folders (Box 1)
    - Handbook on Departmental GSI Development, 1998-1999 (Box 1)
    - A Handbook of Readings for Beginning Faculty, 1993 (Box 1)
    - A Handbook of Resources for University of Michigan Teachers, 1974-1981 (Box 1)
    - A Handbook for University of Michigan Teaching Assistants, 1979-1983; 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Improving Teaching, 1964; undated (Box 1)
    - Teaching Tips by Wilbert McKeachie, 1965 (Box 1)
    - Using Computers for Instruction, 1971-1975 (Box 2)
    - Using MTS (a computer programming system), 1971-1976 (Box 2)
    - Using CRLT's Instructor-Designed Questionnaires to Improve Instruction, 1978 (Box 2)
  - Newsletters (in chronological order)
    - Center for Research on Learning and Teaching, 2002 (Box 2)
    - CRLT Faculty showcase, 2005 (Box 2)
    - TA Training Bulletin, 1983 (Box 2)
  - Reports
    - An Analysis of the Specific Features which Characterize the more Successful Programs for the Recruitment and Training of College Teachers, 1967 (Box 2)
    - Designing More Effective College Instruction Project
      - Report no. 1, Instructor Perceived Needs, 1969 (Box 2)
      - Final Report, 1970 (Box 2)
      - Workbook 1-4, 1970; 4 folders (Box 2)
    - Faculty Development Fund Teaching Award Program Progress Report, 1976-1978 (Box 2)
    - Measure, Number and Weight: A Polemical Statement of the College Grading Problem, 1967 (Box 2)
    - Preparing for an International and Global World: A Survey of Undergraduates at the U. of M., 1993 (Box 2)
    - Report of the Task Force on Testing and Training Prospective GSIs, 2002 (Box 2)
    - TA Training and Development Programs, 1994 (Box 2)